<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Sandesh Sharma</title>
    <link>https://sharmajee499.netlify.app/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://sharmajee499.netlify.app/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://sharmajee499.netlify.app/media/icon_hu5666f1ae0d8e51197792a269747b1cce_24889_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://sharmajee499.netlify.app/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics Presentation</title>
      <link>https://sharmajee499.netlify.app/post/data_analytics_presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sharmajee499.netlify.app/post/data_analytics_presentation/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://sharmajee499.netlify.app/post/data_analytics_presentation/index_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was invited by couples of faculty member from Nicholls State University’s College of Business to present about the Data Analytics. The presentation was all about data analytics future, job demand, scope and resources available at College of Business. I want to thank &lt;a href=&#34;https://cmcastille.netlify.app/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Chris Castille&lt;/a&gt; for arranging this opportunity. I have already given 6 presentation in the various classes like Computer Information System [CIS_231], Business Statistics [QBA_282/283], Management [MNGT_301], Marketing [MKTG_470] and Business Administration [BSAD_101]. I still have two more presentation to give which is on mid-April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video of one of my presentation given on MKTG_470 can be found on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/6E7b6CPwx9s&#34; target=&#34;&amp;quot;_blank&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sorry for the audio quality of the video. I should have presented nearby the mic. There are plenty of mistakes as I was nervous as well as excited. At the end, I would like to thank the respective faculties who gave me a chance to present in their classes. In addition, I would also expand my gratitude towards the students who listened my presentation for 45 minutes. 😃&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with R</title>
      <link>https://sharmajee499.netlify.app/post/install_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sharmajee499.netlify.app/post/install_r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt; is a beautiful and powerful programming language. People always
debate about the Python vs. R. For me, both have advantages in their
respective fields. I have used Python and R for about equal amount of
time. Personally, I find R to be more powerful in data manipulation,
cleaning, summarizing and making statistical models. However, Python is
more easy to work when it comes to deep learning and advance
computational modeling. Moreover, Python is general purposed programming
language meaning, it could be used to make anything. I mean anything
like website, computer software, mobile app, API etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-install-r-&#34;&gt;How to Install R ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One basically needs to download two things to get started with R coding
i.e. R &amp;amp; R Studio. Think R as a engine whereas R studio as the whole car
which supports the engines execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download R from CRAN (Comprehensive R Archive Network)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; website and
download the needed file depending upon your operating system. After you
downloaded, install the file and you are all set for first part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig1.jpg.png&#34; alt=&#34;CRAN R&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download R Studio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now after downloading the R, you are all set to download the R Studio
from &lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com/products/rstudio/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. Install the R Studio
by opening up the downloaded file. There is nothing wierd setting to be
set while installing, go with the flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything goes alright you should be able to set the R environment
for you analytical journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;rstudio.jpg.png&#34; alt=&#34;R studio&#34; title=&#34;Comparison of R Studio Products&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
